Guide to the War Poster Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1915-1944; Accession 2004-M-081
  - La guerre de 1939-1945
    - Proclamation aux habitants de la ville d'Angers et du Département de Maine-et-Loire. La ville d'Angers est libérée et, avec elle, plus de la moitié du département, plus de la moitié de la région..., 1944; 45 x 56 centimeters. (Box 15)
      Artist: Unknown. Printer: Le Commissaire de la République pour la Région d'Angers, Jacquier.
    - Ordre de mobilisation générale, Circa 1939 - circa 1945; 73 x 92 centimeters. (Box 15)
      Artist: Unknown. Printer: République française, ministère de la Guerre, ministère de la Marine, ministère de l'Air. Imprimerie nationale.
- Additional material, Accession 2007-M-065
  Conditions Governing Access
  Accession 2007-M-065 is restricted pending conservation treatment.
  - Two poster boards by Wm. von Cleff, Undated (Box 1)
  - "Charge Yourself with the Duty of Conservation" (colored chalk) (Box 1)
  - "Help Make Him Fit To Do His Bit" (charcoal) (Box 1)
- Additional Spanish Civil War posters, 1936-1938; Accession 2016-M-095
  This accession comprises posters and a broadside from the Spanish Civil War, all in support of the Republican faction. Creators of the posters include Partido de Izquierda Republicana, Asociación de Amigos de la Unión Soviética, Juventudes Socialistas Unificados, and Comité Central del Partido Comunista. Materials date from 1936 to 1938.
  Separated Materials
  Removed poster: "cincuentario de la guerra española, homenaje a las brigades internacionales, 16, 17, 18 y 19 de octubre 1986--Madrid" and placed in MS 352.
  - Escobés, A. Fernández. Umbral no. 17, 1937-11-06 (Folder 1)
  - Andrés, Miguel S. "El Partido de Izquierda viene inspirándose...", Circa 1936 (Folder 1)
  - Spanish Republic, Ministry of Propaganda poster, Circa 1936-circa 1939 (Folder 1)
  - Asociación de Amigos de la Unión Sovietico broadsides, 1938 (Folder 1)
  - Izquerida Republicana, agrupacion de Madrid. "Asturias solo tiene un pensamiento: ganar la guerra...", Circa 1936-circa 1939 (Folder 1)
  - Juventudes Socialistas Unificadas, Secretario de Propaganda, Conferencia Nacional de Juventudes Socialistas Unificadas, 1938-01 (Folder 1)
  - Comité Central del Partido Comunista. "El Partido Comunista dice: Todo el pueblo español...", Circa 1937 (Folder 2)